and I was just supposed to say death
death and I think they turned the
microphone all the way down but still I
was standing there in front of that
audience with Metallica just realizing
wow this is the best Idol that I've ever
heard
[Music]
[Applause]
please
foreign
so I I wanted to I wanted to start off
this episode a little bit by saying you
know into why I'm super hyped to have
you here okay and I actually I don't
know that I've ever I don't know that
I've ever told this story before on the
on the podcast
um but essentially the way that I got
into live hacking events in the in the
beginning was I was a plus one of a plus
one so one of my buddies just kind of
ran into Ted Kramer I don't know if you
remember Ted Kramer yeah and um and yeah
of course how could we forget and um and
he was like
he was like Hey man uh you know I'm a
hacker as well and he's and Ted was like
oh you should come to the live hacking
event in DC and and so he's like great
can I bring my friend Justin or Rhino
Raider I think is what he said and then
at that moment
um John bottarini right John barderini
was standing thereby and he's like wait
did you just say Rhino Raider oh he just
found a really weird bug on like XYZ
Target right and then Ted was like oh
cool well yeah sure you know let him let
him come or whatever right yeah if he
can make it bring it on and so I went to
that live hacking event and uh I somehow
placed eighth and became good friends
with Kevin Rosenbaum right at that event
and they because of that they invited me
to San Francisco
and then when I get to San Francisco
um I get a show and tell right and uh
and after that show and tell I was like
uh you know they invited me to the next
one so I was like okay the show and tell
is the key you know to getting access to
other live hacking events and who is the
master of the show and tell but in T and
every a live hacking event that I went
to you know at the time you were in this
the live hacking event circuit at the
time as well
um inti was getting show and tell after
show and tell after show and tell after
show and tell
um it was sort of like a meme you know
how is into gonna get show and tell this
time
um so that's why I'm really excited to
have you on the Pod because you just
have these crazy
um show and tell bugs and I think it's
left a big impact on all of us that
we're in the live hacking event scene at
that time
um so with that man welcome to the pod
thank you thank you and I gotta say on
the show and tell that the pressure
really helped actually yeah it was a
paradox like At first I didn't like it
because I I knew I you have to perform
for Life hacking events but I also have
that hope you have to hit that goal of
sure and tell every single time yeah
um but in the end you know I always
found a way uh to do it so and yeah I'm
still proud of that yeah most people
have awards for like a lot of
um critical bugs Etc and most of my
bonuses that I've ever got was just like
show about bonuses yeah Phineas they
once they're like the most creative oh
yeah
also known as the Indie award
that that's great man yeah it should get
a trademark yeah seriously and and um no
so I mean and I think Show and Tell has
a really unique part of it's a unique
part of the life hacking event
experience is because it is what helps I
mean obviously you know when you're at
the Live Hack events you're
collaborating with other hackers you're
talking with other hackers as well right
but the show and tell piece you know
um that is what really you know you get
an in-depth explanation with visuals
with uh in your case very engaging humor
and and uh very creative attack vectors
um and that's what helps us grow as
hackers in that sort of context as well
and I know some of the the the times
that I've grown the most from live
hacking events uh is looking at Show and
Tell specifically yours
um so you know the best moment in a show
and tell it's like when you're at like
slight two or three and everybody sees
like a page that everybody literally
everybody
and you just know
oh damn I just realized what I missed
there and everybody is like super
excited yes a little bit dumbed down
because they could have found that dude
I think you did that you used to do that
so well to you know with the show and
tells because it's like and then there's
the moment you go to that slide and
everyone's like ah uh you know like no
like and you can almost hear the vision
I mean you really sometimes you can
you're like what like this place so yeah
yeah I think I think that's such a great
piece I can't even tell you how many
times I've seen a bug in a show and tell
that I've tried like almost like either
that exact same thing on a different
Target or I've tried like I was trying
similar things and I just gave up and I
was like okay I can't get around this
and I just moved on
so it's oh man it's amazing I think the
big thing about your Show and Tell
skills is just like
um you have this amazing presentation
ability where like the Showmanship yeah
like it's it's the Showmanship it's like
you have a very good like speaking
um like experience I don't know your pup
your public speaking skills are very
good and so your way of presenting your
bugs is very ex like everybody can
understand it everybody's very involved
like you really call the whole audience
myself included and so I think yeah
that's just what one of those things
that makes the Indie Show and Tell just
like so much more elevated legendary man
and and so well thank you and it's it's
a nice compliment coming from from both
of you
um and I think that honestly it's in the
show and tell it's more about the story
than the book because in all honesty not
all of my books were great in fact I
think I have the still whole I'm holding
the record of having the lowest ratings
with the highest bonus
I'm quite proud of that so I think that
attack scenario involved like kidnapping
the
and I remember
like telling me like I can't believe
we're going for this man but still they
did it's about the story dude oh my gosh
I just got flooded with memories that I
remember that show and tell there's like
some some like like the character limit
was too long for you to show the
destination of where they were going so
you could kidnapped the queen oh man oh
gosh
um yeah think about the impact yeah yeah
I mean yeah that would be a disaster
um all the royalists would be super nice
that would be terrible it is really
interesting that you point that out
though because I think like there's
always like two aspects to like a bug
Bounty report and a lot of people when
they write a book Bounty report they
think about it like as if it's they're
doing a show and tell like it like
they'll write it out and they'll be like
well I was looking through your website
one day and I came across this really
interesting endpoint and like from a
Report perspective most of the time they
don't really care about that but if you
were to take that exact report and like
put it into a show and tell context it
would probably do like pretty well
because it's very like oh yeah a
storytelling like it explains where you
were coming from as a hacker like the
whole like mind like mental aspect like
how you're approaching the problem those
things really matter for a show and tell
they don't matter so much for report but
I think like everybody kind of has that
ability and it's about sort of like
harnessing it to like show it in the
right way yeah
yeah but still during a live key event I
would argue that you have to I mean that
demon and you you know this best of all
Joe like you're getting hundreds of
reports in a few days and if you want to
get that surrender you gotta ask
yourself the question if you're drafting
a report how can I make this report
memorable yeah without you know
exaggerating too much because then they
will think I'm a stammer a bit like just
in mind but I remember in that report my
title said like literally results in
kidnapping oh my gosh
right away
that's a serious impact yeah I don't
think there's many people who could say
that they reported a bug on hacker one
or any hacking platform that that says
results in kidnapping results in
kidnapping oh my gosh okay
and then I'll let you do your thing
um recently and and this was at um at
integrity and I do have permission to
talk about this great
um but it was with a client of course of
course I cannot tell you which clients
and
um so basically what the hacker reported
was simply like an authorization book I
mean it's like a misinformation check
and we got to the client because it was
fairly critical
and the clients started panicking and
they said the actual impact of this is
that people could die oh no so so that
was their impact assessment and
sometimes if you think about it we big
bounty hunters you know we look at the
idol and we will see okay I can change
this bit of data but if that bit of data
is for example and it doesn't open that
okay if that's for example a blood type
of a person oh yeah in a production
environment yeah and you have a serious
problem and not all hackers think like
that yeah I would say that if you want
to find good books you have to think
like a hacker oh yeah not as a q a yeah
and I have all respect for Q a distance
they can find phenomenal they can
probably get paid more if they think
about the story yeah no absolutely
that's that's uh that's crazy and and
whenever you're dealing with those
products that intersect with with real
life you know like you know sometimes
it's it's information and we'll talk
about information a little bit more
later and and some of your work that
you've done with privacy related stuff
and all that's very important but you
know when it comes down to stuff like
you know like Transportation like
medical stuff like you know all of these
things that interact with with our
bodies right then um Things become way
more critical and it does start it does
start to make you realize that the work
that we do here especially in those
environments uh has a very large impact
on people and I have no doubt that uh
you know bug Bounty reports have saved
lives it's super interesting to me when
we think about like how internet is
starting to affect more and more things
like I know we've talked about like
internet of things and how everything is
more Internet connected but I think
especially now it is it's getting more
and more so where almost everything is
on the internet like
heart pacemakers cars computers phones
cameras door sensors door lock like
everything it's all on the internet and
so many of those things are vulnerable
attack surfaces to the point where even
certain programs will pull things out of
scope like United is a great example
where nothing on the in-flight like
infotainment or any of that stuff is in
scope because they don't want people to
like Risk hacking stuff while the plane
is in the air because there's so much
risk involved there even if the systems
are completely separated they don't want
to even take the chance of like having
somebody test on it it's it's super
super interesting to see how that's
changing over time and how even though
it's dangerous more and more stuff is
going online that probably shouldn't be
online but but is online and now those
impacts of like
chance of death like this is like a real
this is like a real thing and it's not
just like an edge case now
yeah
yeah absolutely and and into you've um
you've worked a little bit with the
United program right have you have you
hacked on them
um I have yeah I have in the pulse um
I'm not sure if I can disclose a lot
about them I think they're they're a
great team yeah their own way of
assessing uh severity yeah
he said he said it's a choice it's a
choice yes
what
so well said
I do have to say there is I always and
you know I as a working at the book
Bounty platform I work with a lot of
clients that may have their reasons
um and Joe I mean you you've also seen
both sides sometimes three hackers
we easily assume or we just take you
don't even want to know how many reports
for example we see like in this cycle
one report or this big crowd people
assessed this way and for some companies
things are just different and what I
just think is really important and in
United States they do point that out in
the in the program uh description and
there'll be friends is
um you have to be transparent it's all
about expectation if you're up front
with the way you score vulnerabilities
even though I as a hacker do not agree
with that then that's I mean no their
problem necessarily I can just choose to
move on and to do something yeah or in
in the case that we saw recently with
Vis being implemented
um in the zoomberg Bounty program
um you can also choose to game the
system with that with that same standard
set of Standards right so you know I
think um you know Zoom users be ISS a
lot of other places use CVSs and then I
believe United uses the owasp model
first yeah risk rating model yeah
um and but each one of these models has
their own
um I guess quirks right
um little weird things that you can do
as an attacker and um one of the things
we saw at the at the zoom event was one
of the hackers Tom Anthony found a great
way to game the system for Vis right and
get bugs rated higher than you would
normally expect them to be to be rated
um and that worked out well for him in
the event and I think that's just a part
of the system right that's a part of the
the game for hackers and and programs
yeah uh I think that's that's uh
Twilight's territory honestly
um because
I mean sometimes and I mean we do see
both sides of the table uh sometimes it
will people will gain the system to
death and if you're a large Enterprise
you can afford that then you know it's
just the running error uh the especially
for smaller companies yeah that hurts uh
while they still care about of course
being consistent it can be a little bit
tricky so I do expect hackers to point
out I mean I prefer hackers to point out
any flaws that they may see in the
policy because we may even give an
additional bonus for that
um it wouldn't be the first time that we
said okay your report resulted in a
policy change we're actually going to
pay out for the policy change rather
than for the book that turned out wow so
I mean even duplicates can sometimes be
very exotic because like sometimes you
will have
it's not necessarily the same root cause
as it's not necessarily the same code
patch but then if you would look to the
process for example on how to the the
they deploy all the instances they could
also have fixed it over there so yeah if
a hacker if a program wakes up with 100
submissions of essentially the same
finding well are they really expected to
pay out to 120 I wouldn't say I don't
think so it would be correct to pay up
one I wouldn't say that they it would be
correct to pay out 120 yeah and
sometimes you got these edge cases and
heck look just to give him a shot has
done a very interesting proposal on how
programs or platforms should deal with
these situations oh really I don't know
that I've seen that you haven't either
yeah he's uh created big Bounty
standards oh yeah I did actually see
that I wouldn't yeah huh yeah it's super
interesting I think it's it's exactly
what you're talking about like you see
this a lot both from like the programs
I'm sure every hacker has kind of dealt
with this situation in one one form or
other but essentially you're put in a
situation where you may have found
something systemic or you may have found
like a repeated issue or something like
that and you realize that this is
something the team cares about and
something that they'll pay for but it
may be very very similar and then you're
in this ethical dilemma where it's like
should I
make as much money as I can here and
Report these things as separate issues
or should I group them together in good
faith and tell the team and hope that
they award me accordingly for that and
they'll probably fix it in one place and
I'll lose a bunch of money but it's the
right thing to do
um and I think that there's no real
clean-cut answer but I'll have to take a
look at um what uh Hackley put together
there because that sounds really
interesting I do agree that like I don't
think it should be really one or the
other should be kind of in between but
it's really hard to Define where that is
and ideally there is also like
consistency across all platforms and
that is also
why at least for the first time with
Integrity
that we have had a meeting in in Las
Vegas during that before the cross yeah
um to discuss some of the I would say
issues that may be more challenges that
we can work on together just so that the
community and the client base and just
the industry as a whole would benefit
from
um and I think we we need to align on on
step like proposals for standards like
that but also other things for example
um we had the unfortunate event that two
life hacking events were colliding so
they were basically doing the same day
yeah but you know a lot of the top
talent is present on all the platforms
and then you know nobody really wins
because there's a platform you see that
your talent may want to go to the other
or vice versa and then the the hackers
are also missing out on that
additionally yeah so yeah I think it's
just good for us to align a bit more and
just work together when it comes to the
community and it's it's been really
great I mean it's yeah there's such
Cooperative wonderful people to to work
together that's awesome and I I was I
the heart was warmed when I saw that
post on Twitter you know with you and
when uh codingo and Jessica and it's
just like you know Mom and Dad and Dad
all living together in harmony and it's
it's great
um and so I mean there's a little swag
I like that that's great
um yeah it so I mean did did that go I
guess that was one of the things I had
on the list to talk about it did that go
like
I mean do you think you'll see that
collaboration was that was that bridge
sort of formed how did that meeting go
from your perspective
um so actually there was already some
sort of collaboration I mean do you
think emailing that's good it's lacking
a lot yeah
um just I mean because if there's for
example new trend in the or a concern
with the community yeah or in the
industry I mean it's it's always best
for us to align
um just I mean nobody literally nobody
wins from having disagreements on a
community level it's also yeah extremely
confusing for the community
ideally everybody has the same
experience regardless of the platform
and mostly also regardless of the
program right
um so I think it's I mean we've been
doing that in a more informal way and it
was just good to now have the
discussions but in person as well and
also go for a more formal approach
meaning that if I suddenly drop that
tomorrow that this thing can be uh right
that's right I'm not planning to it yeah
okay we were talking about death earlier
because of a bug
this doesn't remind as long as the
hackers are doing our jobs
this does remind me a lot though of like
the Safe Harbor discussions that were
happening like a couple years ago before
Safe Harbor was sort of like
a default type of thing across a lot of
programs and platforms
um where everybody was kind of aligned
in terms of like how he felt like things
should be going and how things should be
handled but it was very much so up to
programs and platforms individually to
determine and set out the guidelines and
the guard rails for how things would
actually happen and be like this program
specifically designates Safe Harbor in
their and if they don't then it's not
there right and like I think now that
it's it's been sort of like adopted as
Safe Harbor it's not like a hacker one
thing it's not like a bug crowd of
things on Integrity thing it's just like
Safe Harbor is Safe Harbor and generally
most programs should have it and should
try and adhere to it because that's what
makes security research safe and a
productive thing and I think we're
starting to get there with the same type
of like relationship where the program's
like it really makes me think back on
like the old
um rivalries between like Google and
apple and Adobe and how like apple would
never add flash player into Safari or on
iOS and stuff like that or how like
iMessages with like Android and that
kind of stuff where we're now getting to
a point where Regulators are stepping in
and saying this like type of business
um like disagreement or like business
competitiveness isn't productive for the
rest of the people who are within the
ecosystem and it's time to step past
that and put it to the side and just
like move on and let your business be
competitive in other ways and let there
be certain ground-based factors that are
shared across all of the companies and
across the entire community that
everybody can take advantage of
um yeah and honestly I mean I've I've
been doing this I've joined Integrity in
2017 and maybe I've just been working
but I've rarely come across any form of
um toxic uh competition that's great
um of course I mean sometimes it may
happen that you know a sales person may
say something yeah it's not fully
aligned and then it's almost a better
Coach than Etc but I've always felt like
in the eyes of the community I mean we
share the same super valuable community
and at the end of the day our platforms
right now are still 100
dependent on the willingness of that
community so it's it's community that is
boss and it's up to us to figure out how
we can make sure that we make progress
uh while maintaining the we see our
community as a client and then of course
we also have the client right and
sometimes it's hard to balance that out
I mean I also sometimes read blog
articles from well-meaning
I think hackers saying book about this
should be like this or like this and and
the thing is
like hypothetically I agree with them
they're making good points but then if
you're walking in a platform environment
where you know you have the industry you
have the clients and you need to make
sure that everybody moves at the same
Pace not only the hackers but also the
clients and I think that change can only
accelerate if we ask of the three
biggest platforms can just work together
um so yeah I'm super stoked about this
and I hope to be able to update you on
more progress uh that's awesome man yeah
it seems like we're moving in the right
direction with that and I think that'll
improve the experience for everyone
involved
um so
I I guess we went down a little Rabbit
Trail I'm going to bring it back
um because one of the things we were
talking about in the beginning was your
ability to present and your ability to
do Show and Tell and your public
speaking prowess and I think that's a
pretty core piece of the way that you've
um you know been in the community as a
hacker and I imagine all of that
actually started from your radio
experience and as a podcast you know
we're sort of like I guess radio
adjacent so I I wanna I wanna get some I
want to hear about your radio history
and and how you kind of got into that
that field and in any you know any tips
and tricks you might have picked up
along the way
I mean just to get that out of the way I
didn't have my own show or anything I
was not a radio presenter I worked at
the radio station however okay gotcha
sometimes I was called in to
um tell a little bit about uh like about
cyber security in general there was
something going on like one acquired or
whatever I would typically go and talk
about it uh for National audience yeah
and and basically then the the true
the the challenge was to make sure that
you explain things in a way that is
actually correct while still making sure
that people don't just switch stations
right because you're getting too
Technical and that that is I've I've
learned a lot in that space and it's a
real art honestly because then you also
like if you're not technical enough then
your core fan base or the people that
really appreciate you as a hacker will
start thinking like what is this guy
saying like can't he just give some
proper details and I always love that
balance I think radio for me because
most of the times I was mostly doing the
socials just doing website stuff as well
but I was in an environment surrounded
by passionate people that knew
everything about the subject that I
didn't know anything about which was
music right they were extremely
passionate and like they were the best
of Belgium and what I really like about
Belgium as well is that I mean the best
of Belgium you can there's only 11
million people here right I'm not sure
how many people live in New York but
maybe yeah probably less than that four
times that in California so
um yeah okay but it also I mean I'm
grateful for it because we all still
have stuff like the public broadcast
company and the national stations and it
makes it I guess a little bit easier for
a person like me to step up and to reach
audience and and I would come into the
to the studio and we would talk with if
the Prime Minister Minister of Belgium
with politicians that actually can make
change happen and one of that those
changes that are particularly proud
about and this is not only uh my work
played a very tiny role in that
um is that in authorized testing in some
conditions is now completely legal in
Belgium
um so you can go ahead a bulging company
as long as afterwards you make your
reports and that can be on their
computer there's a couple of rules
attached to it but if there's like a
sales business in Belgium then you can
just if their computers are involving
and you're indulging citizen you will no
longer be prosecuted for for hacking
them and Reporting availability to them
wow which I think is super cool yeah
that's that's awesome and it almost it
almost feels like you know like the
parallel that you hear all the time with
like Enterprise organizations and then
startups right like you know in in
Belgium or I was actually just speaking
to someone the other day from
um uh South Sudan and and they're like
yeah I was like talking to the minister
uh blah blah and I'm like oh really oh
that's cool you know because because you
know in the in these smaller countries
you can get access to you know these
people um a little bit easier and uh and
you can actually influence change which
is really cool
um during your lost life hacking event
in Belgium be almost but then a crisis
happened so it didn't go through but we
almost got like the Prime Minister of
Belgium to just
that would have been pretty sick I think
I think uh I think I was also talking to
somebody who I want to say it was Saudi
Arabia that was at a live hacking event
there and then like one of the princes
or something came by the event and I was
like whoa no way that's that's kind of
nuts
um yeah because I just hope they didn't
have WhatsApp on them yeah I know right
and it's a little bit weird right yeah
it's a little bit it's a little bit
weird right because it's like sometimes
insecurity we feel so niched down right
like we're we're
um you know even within our our
community you know there there are
celebrities within our community and
stuff like that but at the end of the
day we're at very very small community
um and so whenever you know there's
interactions with stuff like that like
people that are well known by the normal
populace right like the prime minister
or you know whoever
um I think that's I think that's really
cool to see that intersection
um yeah yeah okay so that uh that's the
that's the radio that's the radio you
know backstory a little bit so you you
came on you were talking about cyber
security
um in front of a national audience
that's great now I want to hear a little
bit of the hacker backstory so how did
you how did you get into hacking and how
did you land in Buck bounty
um good question
um I guess and I think this goes for for
most of us I'm a cheater but not a
relationship
that that is the disclaimer that I
always have to say
um but I I was never really good at
video games or any games it's just
lacking and then I guess I have enough
time on my hands to try to find a way to
win and it started it started off with
video games do you remember like okay
moment where you know everybody was like
trading oh yes and there was like this
missing no bird like this yeah yep to me
that was just magic that you could catch
a Pokemon that was not in the Pokedex by
by doing what by first going to talk to
an old dude in Viridian time and then
flying over to the other side of the map
to swim I mean it didn't make any sense
and I really wanted to know and by the
way live overflowed the excellent video
on that which we will link in the
description
this guy's a pro all right
um I really wanted to know how that's
how that stuff worked
um and yeah like it just started from
there and then I also figured like think
everybody comes at the point where they
have to decide do I I want to risk it do
I want to become a criminal or not right
but I was well raised by my I lost
tracking I always wanted to break in but
I don't didn't want to break into jail
so um yeah then I found Yahoo uh Yahoo
Yahoo was my first program
um and I got to see they had a thermal
submission form it was like do you know
these mail two links that would um yeah
so you would fit in this form and then
you would press submit and I had like
mail two links of course like any
sensible person either disabled in my
browser so I would fill in the form
click the button nothing happened so I
was just assuming that it was getting
sent because no it was supposed to open
your email client so you had to send uh
no yeah I was pretty disappointed I was
quite happy with the with the larger
Factor one that basically my reports
would arrive and that's how I started
with scripting books
um then I you know I I also did a lot of
thin authorized testing because I didn't
know better yeah of course
I got lucky with that though so I think
one of the best stories there and uh by
the way kids don't don't try this
anymore because it's I guess it's new
management
um and I don't really I've been telling
the story a lot of times and I don't
think he they will allow me in their
concerts anymore but I was a big fan of
of Metallica oh no
um so the the rock and roll or the heavy
metal but yeah today and I knew that
they I had to deal with hackers like a
few years back when when somebody I
think stole their whole album or
something and they had like these meet
and greets and I really wanted to meet
them and it was like an online Lottery
system
and basically I found a way to do some
cheating on the website but at the end
of the day because the ethical hacker in
me uh stood up I was like I cannot take
this spot I need to email the webmaster
and tell tell them what I've done tell
them of course that you know this is not
in bad fate please just fix it and they
said hey you know what empty you can
still come to their show in Belgium
um you can come and mix Metallica
um they sign my keyboard
This is for for the YouTube watching no
way this is like Metallica 2014. whoa
that's crazy
they all loved it they all love this
song that's awesome
I got on stage with them uh and I could
do like the backing vocals of dance
songs
and I was just supposed to say death
death and I think they turned the
microphone all the way down but still I
was standing there in front of that
audience with Metallica just realizing
wow this is the best Idol that I've ever
done so
yeah and that's basically I mean that
was pretty cool swag and they're just
dude then I was I was working at in in a
grocery store I quit my job the same day
I was like I'm going to do this with my
life and I guess it's sometimes timing
and being a little bit lucky and just
keep on I think your first book is the
hardest book and I just you know once I
got there everything followed yeah for
sure I definitely um that's a that's a
common thing that I've seen with new
hackers and I mean old hackers too but
like finding that first bug
some of it is timing and some of it is
just like there is like a natural
like
you know Acumen or whatever towards
hacking where some people just it clicks
like really quickly and they're able to
just be like oh like that's all I have
to that's what's considered hacking I
could definitely do that and then they
just like go do it right and for other
people it takes a little bit and they
like find that first bug and then it
clicks and then they understand that
that's what hacking is but um I think
whatever it is like there's always that
like light switch moment where you find
it finally sort of like you understand
like oh that's hacking like it's it's
just like I always like to say that
hacking is not a skill it's a mindset
and it's a way that you have to think
about stuff like you just have to take
ordinary situations and you have to kind
of like flip it on its head and say oh
okay like if I approach this from a
different angle and I use this system in
a different way I could you know abuse
this in in some unintentional Manner and
I can make it do things that it never
was intended to do or never expected
that it would be doing and that's that's
what hacking is it's it's not like you
know all this like oh I'm gonna put a
balaclava on and sit in the dark
no it's like you know you're just like
putting somebody else's ID in where it
should be or something like that
yeah exactly and and so many people also
think that it's that you need this huge
amount of technical skill set there's a
problem of some people uh lots of people
that I've talked to especially I see
this with cpf players a lot like oh I'm
not good enough yet I need to learn more
but then I will ask them like when you
think you've learned enough because some
of these words are embarrassingly easy
that you know you just need some
persistence I remember this the story
from I mean uh I was just sitting
downstairs and all of a sudden my my
wife came down and she said I found it I
found it I found I was like honey I mean
she works in in HR and Communications by
the way I was like what did you find and
she popped the cross-eyed scripting on
while she was doing online shopping
how did you she was like I saw you doing
that
um remember a couple of months ago when
you I finally asked what is that
mysterious cross-eye scripting thing and
I showed her that she she remembered it
and she was like just entering it in
every single surgical every single month
then she would come across and then
months later he actually found it and
she she then expected the Bounty but I
had to tell her like no honey and all
but yeah the harsh reality and stop
doing this by the way because this will
get you hit yeah exactly wow that's
that's super hilarious though and it is
like you guys are saying that that sort
of you know flash moment and you see it
um something sometimes it comes a little
bit sooner and sometimes it comes a
little bit later and I was talking to a
friend the other day we actually ended
up we actually ended up recording it so
I think we'll probably put out some
shorts or something like that a little
bit later but it was just a really good
authentic conversation with somebody's
somebody who's newer to hacking
but has a high propensity has that that
clearly has that mentality right for
hacking um and he's already found a
bunch of bugs um you know in a hardware
device actually
um just from playing around with it and
bypassing stuff awesome and um and and
uh and I you know we were just kind of
talking about that and I think it it
that is a blessing and a curse that
propensity that that
um you know ability to do it right off
the way right in the beginning because
you know when you when you have a
natural knack for it and you you know
you find some bugs right away you have
to grind a little bit less and then when
you go up against a Target that doesn't
match with your style it becomes it
becomes very disappointing and very
challenging and really um destructive to
your ability uh you know your
self-perception as a hacker right
um and so I yeah it's a double-edged
sword I always say to people that are
kind of coming in and it's great if
you've got it and it but if you don't
you're gonna learn how to you're going
to learn what hacking really looks like
most of the time which is sitting there
reading the JavaScript files playing
with the endpoints opening 500 repeater
tabs until your eyes bleed and then
finally you know breaking in
there's always a better hacker yeah and
you know you may be super happy with the
big that you found or or you may not
find weak uh a book for a week or
something but I especially got this
during life hacking events when you see
maybe you had a bad day or maybe the
target was just not for you and you see
all these people making so much money on
exactly the same things that you've been
looking at and then you know I just
remember I I try to then look at
previous scoreboards and see oh yeah but
in most events they were way behind me
so you know it it just all evens out
nobody can be good at anything my
personal technique was totally different
than other people's technique and
sometimes that technique pays off what I
would do is I would really try to first
set myself an objective uh what what do
I want to achieve I'm the hacker I'm the
attacker like what kind of data do I
want and then I would look for the most
exotic ways to get there like not the
standard ways where I just like
I wouldn't even test like the the search
bar for cross-eye scripting let's say
doing a live tag even because it's even
if it only takes 15 seconds it's gonna
be a waste of time just making an
invoice for that three dollar submit
that you would get yeah exactly so yeah
that's it that's a very important part
and of I think and something we've
talked about as well Joel in the past
these this sort of goal setting piece
and uh and I think it's core to a lot of
hackers mentalities and I think it
really allows you to I I tested this in
a live hacking event recently and I I
achieved both of the goals that I was
going for and I think it allows you to
to really set up something that you want
that's very critical and then and then
get there but but for me it was I only
got those two bugs during this event it
was like those two bugs and nothing else
because I was just laser focused on that
so you definitely do miss stuff when you
go after that but I would rather find
nothing and learn something than finding
a lot of mediums and earning maybe a
little bit more yeah but I've had so
many occasions where I had this great
idea that is totally Show and Tell
worthy and I just can't make it work but
then the next event or the next
engagement I tried that idea again and I
just have you know I save my notes yeah
crazy ideas
um and I test it and it may work on
another Target there's so many times
where I just even after watching other
people's show and tells you go home it
does something on different targets and
it just works and and that is always
nice I've had hackers reach out to me
after life hacking and saying hey you
know what you presented there I tested
it at some of the other targets that I
was working on it worked and they
offered me a 50 50 split which is always
I mean they shouldn't even do that but I
think it's it's quite a nice gesture
yeah and I think that objective-based
hacking I mean it's something that I see
so commonly in so many like of the top
hackers is that like even if it's just
how they started hacking like for
example I very common example that you
gave yourself into is that game hacking
like a lot of people either they're not
good at games so they that's they like
started using cheats or writing cheats
or like getting into hacking games that
way or they want to like you know beat
their friends or whatever like and so
there's like that drive there's like
that objective that like I want to win
at this game how do I win at this game
like let me find all the ways that I can
win at this game and even if it's not
like traditional hacking it's figuring
out ways to exploit the system and to
again that hacker mindset of like
reworking the situation and setting that
objective and figuring out how you can
get there in a creative way that like
still works within the bounds of that
system
um so I was curious to that to that
extent like
for example Integrity xss challenges how
is that like something that
is helping like to train sort of that
skill set while also being like a real
world example do you think that like
having an objective like that is really
useful because it feels like it's
basically the same thing like you have
an objective you know this is vulnerable
to xss the question is how um
um
good question
um I think if so
we've actually stopped doing solely
cross-sized scripting challenges because
people were asking for different stuff
as well the the film thing about website
shipping is that
there's just so many ways and it's it
also I mean whenever we try to do a
challenge we have like one criteria what
do people actually learn from this
and it's not about like in all
transparency it rarely occurs that we
will see one of these payloads actually
ending up working on some of the
programs because they're so exotic but
it does help us filter out the people
that are willing to go that extra amount
of willing to do some research and then
you know maybe then they will put the
same effort into debugging graphql for
example some hackers you can see a
graphql endpoints and there it stops you
know they move on but we really need
these people that are extremely good not
necessarily already have the knowledge
because I guess you can just figure out
most of the knowledge you need on a
specific Target in a week unless it's
maybe harder but even then like programs
like Intel diff setup fantastic
educational tracks for people just to
learn how that stuff works
um yeah I you know I I think it's it's
on the platforms to help educate people
um with challenges but also to enable
Educators because
like we cannot do this alone and that is
like if there's one thing that I'm proud
of with Integrity is that I think we
were one of the first platforms to
actively engage with the Creator
Community like sponsoring people on
YouTube Etc just like in the first place
just to give them something back and we
were so small we didn't have the biggest
bridge but still to you know say hey
this is really cool and it's it's also
interesting to see even as a small
player what kind of an impact that made
on the
right there I say had fluency seen in in
general yeah absolutely and and I really
liked what you were touching on just a
moment ago with you know the access has
challenges they don't necessarily you
know and sometimes they do equip hackers
with knowledge that they need to
actually exploit above on a program but
what they do
um you know what this does result in is
you identify hackers that are willing to
go that extra mile to learn the thing
that they don't know and make that
happen right and I think that's one of
the key skills in in hacking and
especially in bug Bounty is this concept
of like okay I know just from my general
you know inch deep knowledge that this
is sort of roughly possible or I have a
suspicion that this is roughly possible
let's take this larger understanding of
web architecture of you know browser
mechanics of API you know uh structure
and apply it and and try to and try to
learn the details that I need to make
this specific bug work and uh you know
it's it's it's almost never all in the
brain you almost always have to Google
something you've almost always got to
you know fiddle with your your exploit
for you know 20 30 minutes at least and
and I think that's the kind of skill
that really really takes you far in
hacking yeah I would call it like
learning how to brainstorm on your own
yeah lots of people can't like what
really helped for me just to get a
notebook and to just start scribbling
things and and like start drawing
diagrams Etc like okay here's my goal
here's all and just like a lot of people
are very good in the brainstorm love
that they're with the team ah they're
just taking a moment I mean you can also
buy a whiteboard and start like putting
Post-its on that you don't need any
other people from that and sometimes it
can be relieving to be away from the
screen it can be very very stimulating
from your brain to just like I would try
to limit my screen time and try to do
most of the thinking while I was walking
I need to walk around in order for my
brain to function so common yeah I will
say some of the best uh like thinking
like moments I've had or like when I've
like I've had like a light bulb or like
something that's clicked I've been
either on the toilet or in the shower
hour it's like yeah every time I'm just
like sitting there like thinking just
like I've got nothing better to be doing
and then it just like it snaps I'm like
oh [__] uh go and you know pop the bug
man that's sometimes it also brings you
in in embarrassing situations or
uncomfortable situations like I remember
I'm not sure I don't think I can can
reveal the target but basically I found
this vulnerability involving email
bounces uh that would basically result
in a full account
and I was working on that book for like
three or four days already I took the
playing didn't figure it out bought like
the crappy Wi-Fi but it didn't help
that's another 15 bucks lost because I
did I was not able to guess like a
T-Mobile number no usually yeah you just
guess
get in uh not eligible for a big body by
the way
um but I arrived and we went for a drink
with some people that I haven't seen in
years and after this like second beer
like there's something with the second
year always bombers I was I was
distracted I was thinking
book and it's clicked and
I remember apologizing saying I'm so
sorry I have to go to them
I smashed it on there and I ran to the
hotel because I could no longer wait I
had this this thing and it needed to
happen then and that's when it happens
but it also happens you know the feeling
at 2 am right before you want to go yeah
but you find like oh one more request
it's like gamblers like oh one more Spin
and then all of a sudden you're like oh
I'm hitting the jackpot and next thing
you know it's 8 A.M and Mike gets up and
she wonders what the hell have you been
doing oh my gosh dude you know I
definitely I definitely feel that with
the with the uh you know right before
you go to bed so many times I'll you
know be like three right I'll go to bed
this is normally my my Peak you know is
three here like I can't there's no 8 A.M
for Justin Justin goes to bed at four or
you know yeah but uh you know I'll go to
bed I'll go to bed at three I'll be
laying in bed
just as I'm about to fall asleep and
then you know the eyes the eyes shoot
open and I get out of bed and I'm like
I've got it and you go downstairs and
you get it and it's so common you know
you mentioned before as well such a
common theme with top hackers that
um you know going for a walk taking a
shower getting in the hot tub as I
always endorse
um it gets the brains going and
especially when you're trying to exploit
something and you're very close this
isn't necessarily going to help you you
know when you're you don't really have
an active lead right
um not very likely but you know if you
do have an active lead and you're about
to exploit something you just can't get
it
taking that step away helps so much yeah
or talking to somebody about it yeah and
there's a lot of people that want to
collaborate with something that I really
appreciated about life hacking events is
like the the happy hour with the
customer and then you see like some sort
of people some people will just hang
around with the hackers other people if
it's
um one already will spend every minute
of the 60 Minutes they will spend like
screaming the customer talking to them
and seeing like I remembered France
rosen's first question would be where
would you look yeah if you were to find
a critical vulnerability and the very
often they would call it something and
some people would call it social
engineering I call it surprise
collaboration
surprise collaboration I like that you
know
everybody wins
um and typically you know the customers
is very like we recently had the life
hacking event as well and we came up
with the crazy idea hey can we just have
like some sort of system where we can
have hackers grabbed through the source
code if they have a very good suggestion
and I lost how that demos yeah why not I
mean we have NBA science so yeah and
they're like I believe that some people
found some really good bugs because oh
absolutely and I'm looking to extend the
principle depends on whether the
customers wanted or not to other life
hacking events as well because you know
the feeling that you're almost there and
like I can spend another 10 hours on
this or focusing on something else I
want to know how many books people have
lost simply because they didn't find
that last mile little smidges yeah yeah
yeah that's that's brilliant yeah we've
seen this with um well at the most
recent event
um AWS I think we could say this AWS did
this thing called bar raisers
um where essentially they had a couple
people who were employees
um who worked at the company and if you
were really close on something or or you
you felt like you could raise the impact
somehow or you had something that you
just thought like might just need some
some escalation you could bring it to
them and they would help you escalate it
from like an internal perspective like
oh here's what you can do with this like
here's how you can help you know raise
that impact and I think that's so
valuable because
yeah like a hacker can get to that level
I we've we've all seen it like certain
hackers get to the point where they're
like at or beyond what an employee is in
terms of like their internal knowledge
of how the internal systems work but
getting there takes so much time and
effort that having a shortcut makes it
so much easier and such a better hacker
experience to just more productive yeah
like I'm I'm like one step away can you
save me five hours or five days worth of
worth of trying to escalate this and
just like help me help me get that last
bit because if I was a determined hacker
or like a third-party adversary or
whatever I would definitely spend that
time but I don't want to right now and
well yeah I don't want you so much so
much like it just makes it so much
better
it does and it's not just I don't want
to either it's it's also like let's
let's work together to make this a most
efficient process because then you know
is what are you going to do once they
save you that five hours you're gonna go
hack other stuff right and so I have
this conversation with the team a lot
you know in life hacking adjacent you
know sort of scenarios or even live
hacking events um where it's like okay
hey I've got this thing
um and uh I I know it's I know I'm
positive that it's it's gonna be uh you
know exploitable I just need this one
piece of information I can spend five
hours exploiting it or you can give you
know look at the code just tell me what
what you know the route needs to be and
then we can just say you know all said
and done and I go and find other
vulnerabilities for you in that five
hours right
um so it's really a win-win and I'd love
to hear that into you know that you guys
have have integrated that in some
scenarios um at Integrity uh prepping
through source code would be such a huge
asset
um so that's really cool to hear
um so okay so we we've talked a lot
about you know methodology we've talked
about uh you know live hockey events
we've talked about all sorts of fun
things
um
I wanna I I you know like we mentioned
sort of before uh and unlike your
experience on on National Television
critical thinking is a very technical uh
podcast and we'd like to get in the
weeds um about technical stuff so uh I
was thinking when before you came on the
podcast I was like man what are some
cool bugs that Indies found and then
like like you said like 16 of them you
know came into a head
um the ones that I I thought would be
the most interesting would be the ticket
trick
um that weird little CSS injection font
weirdness that you found at that live
hacking event that bug crowd life
hacking event and somehow you're
presenting it to us inside of like a
little little train car do you remember
that that was that was weird yeah I'm
not sure if that one solution yeah I
know yeah yeah that was it was a
surprise show in there it was a little
mini Show and Tell
um and then and then um this um password
slash API key captcha bug so
um I guess you know take your pick where
do you want to start
maybe let's start with the CSS okay
because it's I mean in essence it was
just a terrible bird but it was uh it
resulted in me getting plain text
passwords oh my gosh it's always like
how do you like I've had a few I even
had like a Content reaction that the
actual impact was remote code execution
because you know I could just
inject something in a code that people
were supposed to like copy and paste and
execute as root understand that was my
first live hacking event by the way when
you did that and I was like who the heck
is this guy you know so that's that's
amazing yeah I remember that yeah that
was that was really simple
um but then the CSS one I mean and
I I feel really sorry for the team I
wasn't doing particularly with great and
you know the feeling where you're like
I'm exhausted of this target yeah it's
pretty hardened but I had this one
little book and I was like I just want
to Max this out so road is like nine
page report that I don't think every
anybody read in the amp I think they
just called me and said we don't have
time for this like give us a demo give
us a tldr right we're not going to
triage this I do understand yeah
um but what I did is I I found the CSS
in action and basically the only thing I
could do is
um like add a font and change like the
position and basically style of the page
so was this I couldn't even was this a
CSS injection by a query parameter was
it a post body request was it an upload
it was stored okay basically yeah
um it was like some sort of online
collaboration thingy and I could just in
like as an over platform user I could
send you like an invite and it would
kind of show up on your
um yeah yeah I I basically have like I
could not pop any cross-eye scripting
tried really hard didn't work but I
could mess around with the Styles
um but because it was on the homepage I
was like hmm this is not a login page
but what if I can make it look like the
login page and then I started just
moving all stuff around and around and
around because you cannot like with the
CSS in action you cannot really add
elements easily you have to just work
with the elements and every single
element you can probably like make it
look totally different but then at the
end of the day I wanted to have like a
hundred percent match of the login page
yeah and then I took like a text box and
what was interesting about the textbooks
is that if people it was basically a
form where people I don't remember
exactly what it was but let's say in the
event of me inviting you that you could
type something down like a comment or
something yeah yeah something that I
could see if you would like hit enter
and I would take that as the password
field so
basically then I found the font because
you know nobody would just see their own
password right and submit it like that
it doesn't so I found the form that it's
like all dots like it it really like you
know the black dots if I try to password
and I would just replace for that
specific form field I would replace that
with
um the Black Fox style I think I I made
it for myself it didn't actually yeah
you mentioned that you had yeah
yeah and I hosted it somewhere and it
got loaded and then basically what ended
up happening is that I would send you
this invite you would open your like it
was stored so next time you would go to
the page you would see the login screen
and you just try to log in
um and even though it was not a password
field it would look like a password
field you would Press login nothing
would happen but you had then sent me a
chat message with your plain text
password oh my gosh dude that is like
an amazing vulnerability okay so you you
you send us you know like an invite or
something like that it gets there you
trigger the CSS injection the CSS
injection allows you to reorder elements
so like maybe you like grabbed a div or
something like that you know put it as
white white background overlaid it over
the whole page you know position
absolute right and then you re you took
elements from the page moved them around
put them into spot to make it look like
the home page and then whenever they
would press the submit button or
whatever that would log in yeah is it
the login button right it that would
take their password which was concealed
via a custom font and send it directly
to you
yeah exactly that's crazy oh my gosh
dude I just I I don't know that I fully
understood that when you did that that
show and tell I I have Goosebumps right
now man that is amazing and actually
um and and so but I do remember that day
one thing that I do remember from that
conversation we had in that little weird
train car thing was
um was that CSS is a lot more powerful
than I thought it was right so I've been
looking at CSS and bugs ever ever since
in one of my highest paid bounties at
this point well into the five figure
range was a CSS injection bug
um so thank you for that for one
um but for two this actually makes me
reminds me of a bug that I found that
I'll just mention really shortly quickly
here which is very similar actually
you'd send an invite and it would go to
the home page and it would be stored and
there was a CSS injection
but it was only in an image right so you
could you could Define the background
image right so what I did was I put the
log out URL there right as that
background image so every time they log
in it would go to the home page it would
load up my invite and then it would log
them back out
and so it dosed the whole application
um and and so these sort of like I think
being exposed to these sort of creative
attack vectors like reordering the whole
page or like reforcing the log out
um those those should really expand your
your attack Vector ideation
um and and help you know you understand
what kind of bugs are possible out there
so NT thanks for sharing that man it's
it's not about the work per se because a
lot of people will say oh it's yes
it must be medium that doesn't always
count I mean you will have programs that
are more receptive to the actual impact
and we always encourage them to
um you see when it comes to CBS is it
may be a little bit more tricky because
then you know CVS just doesn't really
consider or at least not a cfsp tree if
like it's the password that you're
stealing or something else and yeah then
maybe you could argue that you could
have full control but you know it can
get messy quite again one last example I
would uh now that I'm thinking about it
about the cool CSS reaction that I once
found that I think got over 5K rewarding
it for 6K that was like in um I won't
tell the service but it was some sort of
documents signing service like I just
knew that it had some legal importance
and I found a way within the PDF that
would first preview to the user before
they would sign it I had this like CSS
reaction
there's not a lot you can do with it
because at the end of the day they you
know they read it and they sign it and
both the CSX injection was present on
the front end and in the actual
downloaded PDF that would be the
official PDF that is now legally buying
so the only thing I did is I put like an
image over the whole screen like over
the whole page
um but then I looked at the user agent
so I this was an externally hosted image
and my user agents would do like
depending on the user agent my my server
would like file a normal contract the
moment they would see it but the moment
that the PDF parser would do its thing
and make everything legal it would see
that it's now like PDF Wiki whatever
like some sort of library and it would
serve a totally different document still
with their signature on it oh no I could
basically have people sign whatever I
wanted just by having a CSS injection
server side as an injection that was
also the front end so just by looking at
the user agent I was able to you know
you know that impact is is quite quite
high of course because you can just and
then you can start gaslighting people
like oh you you didn't read the contract
properly and you can just change it
afterwards it was a message and I'm very
happy that the company properly assessed
that yeah that's a very high impact
phone Joel this makes me think of a bug
I don't know like a bug by John
batterini did he tell you about that bug
last year I don't think he did
okay so John I don't know we gotta have
John on the podcast sometimes but the
tldr of it with with being uh you know
vague is that he found a way to force
the company to violate a bunch of like
standards that the government has set up
that have penalties in place right so
he's like he's like I I I submit this
request and it sends off this chain that
like registers something with some
third-party you know government thing
right and essentially because there was
a rate limiting bone there he could do
it a bunch of times and it would result
in just like massive fines for the
company like 15K a pop sort of sort of
uh fines for the company and they like
like he reported this bug and the legal
team like was in contact with him within
the next like you know five hours like
please you know let's have a
conversation about this and I just think
like that is like such a John Bug for
one you know like just very thoroughly
the understanding
the whole system even to the point where
you understand the fines that are in
place in you know from a governmental
perspective that affects the sort of
functionality so yeah it's beautiful to
see bugs like that I think one of the
things that I love about sort of all the
books that we're talking about right now
is that
if you were to take this from like a
purely like a bug like classification
standpoint like what kind of bug is this
probably most of them would just be like
immediately considered like out of scope
or whatever because like yeah fishing or
Lowe's or HTML injection or whatever
right but it's not it's not about that
it's about
figuring out like what is the security
impact what is the risk model for this
company and how do I Target my bug to
apply perfectly to that risk model even
if classically it would be like out of
scope how can I make it in scope by
figuring out the way that to make it
impactful for this company and I think a
lot of times
Packers will find a bug they'll be like
ah this is you know HTML injection let
me move on find something more severe
find an eye door or whatever and they
just like leave it as is but if you
stick around and you like really persist
and you take a little bit of extra time
and effort and you figure out what is
that right model how do I apply this to
the threat model in a meaningful way you
can really escalate the impact of those
bugs to take something that would
typically probably not even be worth a
bounty might not even be worth a report
and turn it into something that is super
critical super high like definitely
worth a bounty and one of those like
forever stories that you're gonna tell
about an awesome bug that you found and
how you escalated it
yeah yeah absolutely and I think that
making that translation between a risk
model and program guideline is still
something that we as bookbound the
platforms is a you know that's a problem
that we need to solve
um it's it's a really difficult problem
because you know CBS is quite you know
in terms of expectation Arrangement at
least you can debate about metrics and
still it's not perfect I'm looking
forward to see a business before but
then again how do you like properly
translate because not every company as
well is like I understand this willing
to share their risk model with the
outside world especially if they have
like uh
program so I think that like in terms of
transparency that is still one of the
challenges or unsolved problems that
we'll have to tackle in the next few
years yeah yeah I totally agree
um so
let's let's hop back over to another
another one the ticket trick I think
this is probably the the bug that you're
most well known for uh having having uh
found it you know discovered it built
the logo for it you know got it got it
out there yeah
[Music]
um initially I wanted to uh and the
report was public initially I believe I
I wanted to name it a horrible decision
I wanted to name it slack goal oh wow I
thought I thought he was gonna say I
wanted to dream it horrible decision I
gotta say about it that's one way to
describe bugs
the slacker Corporation rightfully did
not agree Blackjack if it was not even
their their problems right you know no
we went for tickets that's great so so
just give us a little
um a little high level overview of that
and then maybe you can talk about some
of the ways that you've used that bug to
gain access to organizations
um again it started with I was just
bored then I picked a random program
which was gitlab and I think it was even
like a GDP back then
um and I saw that they had like this I
was you know I'm I've always been
intrigued by by emails I think there's I
found a lot of lots of books but I think
my most interesting books had something
to do with email but it makes emails so
interesting is that basically bypasses
all the Security application logic like
stuff like 2ab Etc if I can get it to
your email I can probably like reset
your password but also like there's a
whole bunch of information on these
email systems will just save like links
to exports whatever
um so I was always intrigued by that and
I saw this this feature of gitlab that
you could send something to an at
gitlab.com email address to like create
a ticket so I'm just messing around with
that at first I was like trying to send
over like payloads
um attachments with a page profile you
know whatever you realize that gitlab is
that I was a skip back but then I was
like but what can I like this is a
behavior and a behavior plus a good
story can be a probability
and that is actually what it turned out
to be because then I was also like okay
what kind of other data do they have and
where where are these people working
with or what are they working with on a
daily basis I was going to their job
section doing some reconnaissance there
and this you know they were presenting
themselves they're quite transparent
wide open and they said you know we do a
lot of things through slack so I went to
their slack page I was like I want to
get into this this slide there would be
so much interesting information in there
uh
and of course there's a couple of ways
to do it the traditional ways are just
like maybe trying to hijack a work
integration try to hijack the accounts
but I saw that anybody will add gitlab
accounts could simply sign up so I was
like hey let me like grab this email
address that I got for my ticket tracker
on the gitlab and it was like a very
long email address and pasted it in
there because it was a valid at
gitlab.com email address so I pasted in
the nerves I I checked I pressed okay I
want to sign up for this like like said
okay we've sent a registration email to
them email address and surely enough a
new ticket will got opened on my
instance saying hey welcome to the
gitlabs because you know it wasn't valid
at gitlab.com email address and yeah
that's how I don't do their slack
um they were still VDP back then they
went to to paid program like a couple of
months no ah but I told the CEO which is
a really cool dude
um I met him during a life hacking event
like in a in some sort of Carol keyboard
it was a weird setting and I told him
about this like yeah I probably got you
one of your most impactful books outside
of the platform yeah and I got nothing
for it because you were still a bdp and
the cool thing then was you here and
like he took his wallet took a hundred
dollars in cash and just happened no way
thank you so much and okay it was only a
hundred dollars but we didn't have to do
that we still did it then I really
appreciate it that's that's so
meaningful what an amazing way to
connect with the hacker there that's
because it was his own money so yeah he
couldn't get expensive that right so
that's really appreciated that's so cool
man what what a what a cool guy and what
a great story and what a great bug
um yeah I've always been fascinated by
that and I've never actually found one
myself I've read your research time and
time again but I've never actually gone
down the you know
um uh you know the rabbit hole to find
one and the reason for that is is and
I've seen plenty of places where I can
do like
um you know send an email to you know at
whatever.com
um sort of situations but the problem
for me is I have a hard time finding
um things like slack and like you know I
think maybe Asana was vulnerable for a
little while or something like that
where I can utilize that email so so how
do you how do you do that
so the thing is like actually mitigated
the part of the problem
um they didn't have to do this right now
if you were to sign for slack
um you will get like an invitation email
and just let's say like no reply Dash
and they've done a very low random token
at slack.com
and I really appreciated that because
even though it was not necessarily their
problem that's a misconfiguration on the
client side they still understood that
this could have been really impactful
and they implemented they changed the
way that they so I I could basically no
longer sign up for certain services with
for example nor Appliance link.com so I
would just get a ticket and that would
make typically make it a little bit
harder
um but yeah it's been
it's it's it's one of these books where
not a single instance is the same
um and the impact can
can be greatly this different with like
the base scenario is typically
look if you sometimes what happens is
that a company has like a help desk and
they have typically the the
the user management system is not
brokenly aligned because companies don't
really build that themselves they still
need a way for users to to give their
tickets and what sometimes ends up
happening is that people have an account
on the platform itself but not really on
the ticket portal on the service desk so
what you can sometimes do if you know
where to find like the salary
registrations or API endpoints for these
things you create an account in their
name sometimes they will not require you
to validate your email address and then
you can see all of their Open tickets
which is or every email that they sent
you that email address to like support
ads you can you can hijack but also
knowing that people will send stuff like
gdpr requests Etc to there it's always
interesting to try to sign up with a
victim email on the support instance
because that you can start intercepting
emails to support ads from that email
address
Yeah well yeah that that that's
extremely impactful and all these all of
these email things are super fascinating
I know we've only got I think you have a
hard stop in 10 minutes so
um I do want to and unfortunately we're
not gonna get to everything that we that
we had on the list for today but I do
want you to give us a quick overview of
the time you used to captcha to phone a
company can you can you tell us a little
bit about that
yeah absolutely uh it was like uh some
sort of password manager and one of the
I was just browsing around and I saw
that my own like best Facebook password
was being displayed in play text on the
website so just like in an API endpoint
and that's normal right because password
managers in essence they have to do that
yeah you know that's that's the only
company that has a valid use case
I don't think that's normal
yeah yeah but yeah
it makes sense yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
exactly that's literally like the only
case and still then I think there's like
some mitigations around it so to thank
them it was pretty normal
um so I was looking at my own password I
was like oh damn like I cannot like it's
really pretty bad because if somebody
has like a scripting work on that asset
you can just grab it but that was not
the game it was pretty well isolated but
I did notice that you could embed it
into any page so you could just put it
in like an iframe and then I could for
example no extreme options okay like
Justin here's your Facebook password.com
and I would literally show you your
Facebook password
just by embedding that on my page but
you know how sandboxes work is that I
couldn't act like as the owner of the
website I would not be able to access
that information I could only display to
you so that that is of course where your
hacker mindset has to start popping up
and then that you have to figure out
okay I can display this to my Victim how
can I make them give it to me and
naturally I was just thinking of
captures because that's the only kind of
scenario where somebody is showing
something and they type it back to you
right but nobody literally nobody would
ever just be like oh let me solve this
captcha and be like oh that's fine
I mean unless you use one of these
randomly generated then it's quite funny
so I made this whole peer receiver I
would like isolate because I knew how
um why the top letters were
I would isolate all the lenders like
work with the average length of a
password and added something more to
them and then try to fit them all like
in a capture box applied a whole lot of
CSS CNS on the phone
um like filters on it to make it seem a
little bit distorted so every letter
would be tilted and you know distorted
at a different degree so it would look
like like a village it looks like a
caption too man I swear to God so it
looked so much like a captcha yeah I
would also like flip them around so so
all letters would be at random positions
and people would really recognize the
passwords anymore you know if you're
filling in a caption you don't expect
this but certainly you won't think oh
maybe this is an anagram
so yeah it just it just worked and I I
was able to during the show and tell to
present like this capture that would
actually speaking it was password and
they would put it in and sit with the
plain text Facebook wow oh my gosh dude
that's amazing could you yeah can you
imagine typing in a caption be like wait
this is
this is a perfect anagram for my
password you know like that that's
hilarious and I think you know another
way you could even and I don't think
this attack works anymore because of the
way same site um cookies would work you
wouldn't be able to iframe in a page and
have the cookie still sent to it
cross-origin but unless they have same
site set To None on those cookies but
um you know the other thing was like
everyone knows that time when they have
to submit a caption like two or three
times too so if it was longer right like
you could you could say all right the
first eight characters are going in this
one and then they you know they submit
it and it's gonna be like no that's not
good and then and then try again and
then yeah it's the next eight characters
or whatever and like you could you could
get up to like you know 16 you know 20
something uh you know length of
passwords
yeah and you you presented this at a
live hacking event and it looked exactly
like a captcha and I was like I would
absolutely do this you know like and
it's that was terrifying to me
I believe I called it the gotcha we
gotcha that's it dude gotcha so freaking
good amazing
um cool well that's awesome man I know
yeah we only had a couple go ahead Jill
well I was just gonna say like before we
run out of time I did want you to talk a
little bit about the upcoming live
hacking event for integrity I know we're
like kind of hard pivoting here but
again we only have a couple minutes so
would you mind giving us sort of a
rundown of sort of what's going on and
what's coming up and all that kind of
stuff sure
um yeah I'll just give it tldr because I
do have a hard stop but um yeah we're
running a pretty exciting laughing
events with uh with Intel in October uh
invisible yeah it's gonna be the first
biggest life hacking event uh ever or
we've got education life like events or
smaller skill uh things with them before
but this this one is going to be insane
the targets I can tell you are going to
be very good oh my God we always try to
take care of our hackers as well making
sure that they not only get the
opportunity to find really cool books
but also get the opportunity just to
have fun and to socialize and basically
do that community building around the
Intel program
um yeah and one of the things and maybe
that's the last thing I can say about
that one of the things that I really
appreciated about
um this this kind of event is that
basically Intel is kind of democratizing
Life documents a little bit so they're
like for local hackers and for people
that happen to be around Etc and they
could just like apply for non-sponsored
conceits yeah I know that there's always
this this mysterious group of people
that always gets invited to life hacking
events and even there we have rules for
but to some people it seems like it's
you know we're just inviting our friends
and that's already true there's a lot of
parameters that come into play but still
people sometimes really love to go and
what I really love about this concept is
that people can just pay for their
flights and go there and have fun and
and do it and I yeah I really think that
is a cool concept that we are exploring
for other events as well because I think
that everybody at least should have the
chance in their life to attempt one of
these yeah dude that that's awesome I
know so many people really appreciate
that I've been talking to people and
that has been making a Ruckus in the
community for sure you know people are
really excited about that Joel and I are
both going to be there we're both uh
very excited for it
um so yeah really looking forward to it
uh empty thanks for coming on man we can
find you actually you have two twitters
so I don't know which one you want to
call out yeah so I have ntbc but that's
my Dutch because I speak in English it's
quite confusing so that's that started
off as my radio guys okay that is also
why I have a huge uh [__] follower
based on right I've made feeling rich
but everything big Bounty related is
going to be secure in Secure NT on
Twitter okay awesome anything else you
want to you want to shout out with your
socials or or Integrity or anything
shout out shout out to you guys for
setting this up and creating content uh
for the rest of the community I think
it's super valuable I love what you guys
have been doing and I'm looking forward
to see more of it in the future you guys
are right thank you uh thanks auntie
thank you very much that's that's that's
awesome man um we'll definitely be
looking forward to the live hacking
event and uh seeing you on the Integrity
platform yeah see you soon all right CNN
soon bye
that's the part
[Music]